Finding Aid for Leon Ramsey papers, 1917-1919 and 1960s?
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Leon Ramsey papers 1917-1919 and 1960s?
Ramsey, Leon, 1897-
.2 linear ft.
Soldier from Armada, Mich., member of Headquarters Company, 339th U.S. Infantry who served in the Allied intervention in Russia, 1918-1920, the "Polar Bear Expedition." Collection includes correspondence describing his experiences in the army during training at Camp Custer, Mich., and during his service in Russia; also miscellanea, photographs, and a paper based on Ramsey's correspondence, probably written by John O. Ramsey.
9526 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was donated by John Ramsey, of La Canada, California, in 1995 (Donor no.: 8362 ).
The collection is open for research.
Resident of Armada, Mich., served with Headquarters Co., 339th Infantry.
Correspondence describing his experiences in the army during training at Camp Custer, Mich., and during his service in Russia; also miscellanea, and a paper based on Ramsey's correspondence, probably written by John O. Ramsey. Photographs include a portrait (in uniform) and postcards of Camp Custer, Mich., and Archangel.
Subjects
Ramsey, Leon, 1897-; Soviet Union--History--Allied Intervention, 1918-1920.; Fort Custer (Mich.); World War, 1914-1918.; Polar Bear Expedition.
Genre/Form:
Photographs
- Correspondence
  - Sept.-Dec. 1917, 17 items (Folder 1)
  - Jan.-Apr. 1918, 18 items (Folder 2)
  - May-Aug. 1918, 18 items (Folder 3)
  - Sept.-Dec. 1918, 13 items (Folder 4)
  - Jan.-Apr. 1919, 16 items (Folder 5)
  - May-Dec. 1919, 6 items (Folder 6)
- Miscellanea
  - Miscellanea, 17 items (Folder 7)
  - Service record, 7 items (Folder 8)
  - Paper, by John O. Ramsey?, 1960s?, 1 items, 55 pages (Folder 10)
    (Includes photographs)
- Visual materials
  - Photographs and postcards, 6 items (Folder 9)